<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>io.github.streetpea.Chiaki4deck</id>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">chiaki4deck.desktop</launchable>
  <name>Chiaki4deck</name>
  <summary>Free and Open Source Client for PlayStation Remote Play modified for Steam Deck</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <developer_name>Street Pea</developer_name>
  <url type="homepage">https://streetpea.github.io/chiaki4deck</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/streetpea/chiaki4deck/issues</url>
  <description>
    <p>
      Chiaki4deck is a fork of Chiaki, adding features for the Steam Deck. It is a free and Open Source Client for PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 Remote Play. It can be used to play in real time on a PlayStation as long as there is a network connection.
    </p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/streetpea/chiaki4deck/main/assets/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <update_contact>streetpea@proton.me</update_contact>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release date="2024-5-26" version="1.7.1">
      <description>
        <p>This release provides the following improvements:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Remote connection via PSN now supports PS4 consoles</li>
          <li>Remote connection via PSN now supports more network types</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2024-5-12" version="1.7.0">
      <description>
        <p>This release provides the following improvements:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Remote connection via PSN now available without the need for port forwarding</li>
          <li>Allow zooming out from resolution for users targeting a resolution beyond their screen resolution (i.e., 1080p on Steam Deck)</li>
          <li>Create a fallback session id when session id isn't received instead of erroring out</li>
          <li>Workaround patch for vulkan ffmpeg hw decoder bug affecting Nvidia 30 series graphics card users</li>
          <li>Fix issues with address when registering manual consoles</li>
          <li>Update steam shortcut creation to cover additional edge cases</li>
          <li>Add additional option for obtaining the PSN AccountId via logging in with your psn username and password (in addition to the public lookup)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2024-4-06" version="1.6.6">
      <description>
        <p>This release provides the following improvements:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Enable using mtu as low as 576</li>
          <li>Enable gyro on Steam Deck automatically (can now set gyro to none in Steam Settings and still use native gyro)</li>
          <li>Adjust haptic rumble to work better with rumble motors</li>
          <li>Add variable zoom (accessible via Stream Menu)</li>
          <li>Fix issues with address when registering manual consoles</li>
          <li>Update steam shortcut creation to cover additional edge cases</li>
          <li>Add option to reset key mappings to default in Settings</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2024-3-20" version="1.6.5">
      <description>
        <p>This release provides the following improvements:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Provides quiet haptic rumble for Steam Deck (default) in addition to optional noisy haptics</li>
          <li>Allow escape key to be selected for key mappings in Settings</li>
          <li>Add option to start the stream with the mic unmuted</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2024-3-15" version="1.6.4">
      <description>
        <p>This release provides the following improvements:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Adds create Steam Shortcut option for Linux and Mac</li>
          <li>Allow setting console pin for console in settings</li>
          <li>Add window type option in settings (fullscreen, stretch, zoom)</li>
          <li>Fix issue causing extra blank ip manual console added when registering non-manual console</li>
          <li>Add option to adjust when Wifi connection symbol appears based on % of dropped packets in 200ms interval</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2024-2-2" version="1.6.3">
      <description>
        <p>This release provides the following bug fixes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Trade-off minor image artifacts for smoother stream</li>
          <li>Fix race condition causing remote play on console has crashed</li>
          <li>Fix issue where dropped packets results in losing mic connection</li>
          <li>Correctly set render preset</li>
          <li>Set Dualsense microphone and LED to match microphone mute status</li>
          <li>Add alternate option of using flipscreen.games to query PSN Login</li>
          <li>Correctly replace old reference frames and update bitstream parsing</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2024-1-21" version="1.6.2">
      <description>
        <p>This release provides the following bug fixes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixes framepacing regression introduced in 1.6.0</li>
          <li>Dualsense haptics now work again</li>
          <li>Corrects stretch and zoom when using stream command</li>
          <li>Report corrupted frames earlier resulting in less frames dropped when a corrupted frame occurs</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2024-1-17" version="1.6.1">
      <description>
        <p>This release provides the following bug fixes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixes console registration</li>
          <li>Fixes fullscreen double-click and F11 shortcuts</li>
          <li>Adds option to sleep PlayStation when sleeping Steam Deck</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2024-1-15" version="1.6.0">
      <description>
        <p>This release brings a new user interface to Chiaki4deck including:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New touch-friendly and controller navigable GUI</li>
          <li>Resume connection from sleep mode on Steam Deck.</li>
          <li>Ability to login to PlayStation for account ID via GUI.</li>
          <li>Fix Senkusha, lowering time for console connection and properly setting MTU</li>
          <li>Audio Switch to SDL including fixing audio lag building over session</li>
          <li>New Logo</li>
          <li>Qt6 support</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2023-12-15" version="1.5.1">
      <description>
        <p>This release provides a workaround for the following gamescope bug:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Swapchain for HDR surface hangs on creation.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2023-12-10" version="1.5.0">
      <description>
        <p>This release brings HDR to Chiaki4deck including:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Adds HDR support for Chiaki4deck perfect with the Steam Deck OLED.</li>
          <li>New libplacebo vulkan renderer with better picture quality due to post-processing techniques like debanding (now the default renderer)</li>
          <li>Adds option to use controller by positional layout instead of button labels (particularly for Nintendo-style controllers)</li>
          <li>Adds launcher script for appimage</li>
          <li>Adds vulkan video decoding for video cards that support it (Steam Deck doesn't)</li>
          <li>Implements basic FEC error concealment to improve streaming experience (white flashses / green blocking)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2023-10-17" version="1.4.1">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bug:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Steam Deck shake not detected in certain games because acceleration value was too low.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2023-10-12" version="1.4.0" />
    <release date="2023-9-30" version="1.3.4" />
    <release date="2023-7-16" version="1.3.3" />
    <release date="2023-6-14" version="1.3.2" />
    <release date="2023-1-17" version="1.3.1" />
    <release date="2023-1-08" version="1.3.0" />
    <release date="2022-10-13" version="1.2.0" />
    <release date="2022-09-14" version="1.1.0" />
    <release date="2022-08-25" version="1.0.0" />
  </releases>
